Okay, so let's go ahead and practice
using the Beanstalk service.
So I'm gonna go into the Elastic Beanstalk console
and we're going to create our first application.
So we have an option
to choose either a Web server environment
or a Worker environment.
So right now we want to run a website,
so we'll choose Web server environment,
but if you wanted to process tasks off of a queue,
then we would choose a Worker environment,
but we will only do Web server.
So let's create an Application,
and this one is called MyApplication.
Okay, so next, we scroll down
and we have Environment information.
So the Environment is sort of filled,
but I'm just going to call this one MyApplication-dev
because this is going to represent
my development environment.
A Domain name is going to be automatically generated
for my application,
and this is how I will access my web servers.
Okay, so we scroll down
and now we need to choose a platform.
So this Platform is going to be managed
and I will choose Node.js,
and then I will just choose the default options.
You may see something different than me,
but by using the latest defaults,
you should be fine and good to go.
Next, we need to choose some Application code.
So I'll use a Sample application.
We can definitely approve that on code,
but we don't have that right now,
and so this Sample application will be matching
the environment I have right here.
Okay, so let's scroll down.
We have Presets and Beanstalk can be quite complicated
for the configuration, and as such,
we can set recommended values
for either a single instance, which is free tier eligible,
or high availability where we have
a load balancer for example,
or custom configuration
if you wanted to customize everything.
Now to keep things simple,
we're going to go over Single instance.
So click on Next,
and next we have a tricky bit.
We need to configure the Service access.
So it's the IAM roles that will allow Beanstalk
to do what it needs to do.
So it's very simple.
We can just go ahead and create a new Service role,
and this will create the elasticbeanstalk-service-role.
Now, I think that right now this is a new console,
so there may be a bug, and this is not pre-filled,
so we need to go ahead
and create manually the EC2 Instance profile.
So as such, I'm gonna go into the IAM console,
and on the left hand side I will go into Roles
and I will Create a role
and it's for a service, it's for EC2, you click on Next,
then for Permissions policy, you just filter,
and you type in beanstalk,
and you need to add the WebTier, the WorkerTier,
and the MulticontainerDocker.
This should be enough to get started.
So we click on Next,
and then for the role name,
enter aws, then elasticbeanstalk-ec2-role,
with hyphens in between.
Okay, so now we go ahead and we Create this role,
and this role right here is going to be the one
we're using in Beanstalk.
So I'll go back here, I refresh this,
and as you can see, it got prefilled,
so the aws-elasticbeanstalk-ec2-role.
So once you've done that, you're good to go.
If you clicked on Next, you would have to go over networking
and database and instance traffic, scaling,
all these kind of things but they're optional.
And right now the thing we're going to do
is just click on Skip to review
because we just wanna use the defaults that were set
for the single instance mode.
So make sure under Service access
that you do have the Service role
and the EC2 instance profile selected,
and when you're good to go,
you can definitely look at those, but they're complicated.
Click on Submit and this will go
and create our first Beanstalk environment.
So now if we scroll down under Events, as you can see,
some events are happening
and these events actually come from a service
called CloudFormation.
So if you go into the CloudFormation console,
we can see our Elastic Bean Stack right here,
so I'm going to just go on the right hand side
and make it bigger.
So under Events, if you're clicking fast enough,
you will still see that stuff is being CREATED_IN_PROGRES,
And then once stuff is done being created,
it goes to CREATE_COMPLETE.
So this is the line of events of all the things happening
within your CloudFormation template,
and all the things that is being created by CloudFormation.
CloudFormation is a service we'll see later on.
But here on the Resources,
we can see we have created an Autoscaling group,
we have created a LaunchConfiguration and so on,
and Elastic IP and so on.
One thing you can look at is under Template,
you can view the template in Application Composer,
and the cool thing about it is that we can visually see
what is being created by CloudFormation.
So we can see for example,
that we have a LaunchConfiguration,
we have SecurityGroup, we have an Elastic IP,
a WaitCondition, and a ConditionHandle.
So this is very handy to start visualizing
what Elastic Beanstalk is creating for us behind the scenes.
So now let's go back into Elastic Beanstalk.
So in the Events tab as we can see now,
we have some information.
For example, a SecurityGroup was created
and then an Elastic IP was created.
Then we wait for the EC2 instances to launch,
and then the instances will be created.
So if I switch now and I go under EC2,
the EC2 console,
and look at my Instances running, actually yes,
one of my Instances is running,
it's using a t3 micro,
and as we can see,
this Instance has a Public IP address right here.
And if I go on the left hand side under Elastic IPs,
we can see that this Elastic IP address was created
and is allocated to our EC2 Instance.
And if I go under Auto Scaling groups,
we can see that an auto scaling group was created.
And this Auto Scaling group under Instance management
is managing my only EC2 instance.
That's what it's called a single EC2 instance.
So all of this makes sense
and that's what Beanstalk is created.
And at the end of it, when everything is launched,
you'll say, "Okay, successfully launched,"
and it will be Ok for Health,
and what we get out of it is a domain name.
So if I click on this domain name
and open it in a new tab,
I get actually access to my Beanstalk environment
and my single EC2 Instance, and it says,
"Congratulations, you are now running
Elastic Beanstalk on this EC2 Instance," which is amazing.
So you can see very simply,
Beanstalk was creating for us just from the code,
the sample code that we were using,
it generated all the infrastructure
to start successfully my application, my web server,
which is very, very good.
So now let's have a look at a couple of options.
So if we wanted to upload a new version, we click on here,
we could upload a new version
and automatically it would be deployed to my EC2 Instances.
So we don't have that, but just to give you an overview.
Health gives you some information around the health checks
of all your instances if you had many.
You can go under Logs to view the logs
of your application.
You can go to Monitoring
to have a look at all the metrics for your application.
So we get really like some view centric
around all MyApplication itself.
The Alarms, Manage updates,
which is when Beanstalk, the sets,
that sets you update our entire environment.
And then if you click on Configuration,
you can actually have a look at all the configuration
of your Beanstalk environments, modify them and apply them,
which are quite, quite well-rounded,
but we don't need to know about this right now.
Now, more importantly, if we go under MyApplication,
as we can see right here, there's MyApplication-dev.
That's one environment, but I could go ahead
and create a second environment,
for example, MyApplication prod,
and that will allow us
to really think about environments overall.
So that's it for an overview of Beanstalk.
So to reason about it, Beanstalk is centered around code
and environments for your code.
Whereas if you wanted to look at CloudFormation,
the service we had seen before,
CloudFormation is used to deploy stacks arbitrarily
with any kind of infrastructure.
So we've seen all that Beanstalk has created,
including my AutoScanning group, my EC2 Instance,
the Elastic IP and so on.
And so if you are in a course
that has more Beanstalk lectures,
so for example, the Certified Developer Course,
then do not delete your application,
we'll be using it more.
But if you are done with the Beanstalk lectures,
you've known enough for the exam.
So what you can do is take your application, do Action,
and then Delete application,
and then you will have cleaned up.
So that's it.
Make your own call, and I will see you in the next lecture.